JISU RYOU

+821042422173 jisuryou7@gmail.com Portfolio Page I'm a junior **UX engineer** with a Master's degree in Al application. Over the past few years, I've primarily focused on **conversational Al**, including chatbots and voice agents. However, I'm also skilled in user experience insight research and front-end development. For more information about me, please check out my portfolio:)

EDUCATION

Seoul National University, Korea - Sep 2021~Feb 2024

Master of Engineering

Dept. of Intelligence and Information, The Graduate School of Convergence Science and Technology (GSCST)

Advisor: Prof. Joongseek Lee

* (Best Paper) Study on a VA Journaling System: Focusing on Response Styles for Receiving Long Entries in VA Journaling

Sungkyunkwan University, Korea - Mar 2017~Aug 2021

Bachelor of Engineering and Bachelor of Science in Psychology (1st) Dept. of Software, College of Software Convergence (2nd) Dept. of Psychology, College of Social Sciences

The University of Texas at Dallas, United States – Jan 2019~May 2019 Exchange Student

EMPLOYMENT

SNU UXLab, Seoul, Korea – March 2024~Aug 2024 Project Manager (PM)

- Led the project 'Financial Hyper-Personalization Using MyData' with HiUX, focusing on enhancing contextual data through a notification-based financial management app
- Led the project 'UX Evaluation of Text-Based Conversational Experiences'
 with LG, researching and defining evaluation methodologies for
 ChatThinQ, a custom Home IoT LLM service

Rihoz, Seoul, Korea – Sep 2020~Dec 2020 Web Front-End Developer (Intern)

• Contributed to the project 'Dangjib', a big data-driven smart life service platform, focusing on front-end development of the admin web page and the production app

PUBLICATION

Ryou, J., Lee, K., & Lee, J. (2023, April). "You said da da...": A Short Echoing Tweak for Journaling with VA. In Extended Abstracts of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (pp. 1-6). [paper]

Lee, K., Ryou, J., & Lee, J. (2023). Study on the Mind-Upload of Construction-Building Method: A Case study on the Voice-based Conversation Robot Exhibition. In *Design Convergence Study*, 22(4), 59-73. [paper]

Kim, M., *Ryou, J., Lee, K., & Lee, J.* (2023). Actually, Clustering is Not Everything! How UXer analyzes behavior types with page log data. In *HCI KOREA*, 497-502. [paper]

Ryu, M., Park, S., <u>Ryou, J.</u>, & Lee, J. (2022). "Not a Replacement, But a New Form of Banking": Exploring VUI Use Cases for Banking via Human-Machine Communication. In *HCI KOREA*, 305-311. [paper]

Joongseek Lee, Minjoo Kim, <u>Jisu Ryou</u>, Kihun Lee (2023). 『1인가구와 기술: 혼삶의 시대, 기술이 만드는 이웃감』. threechairs. [book]

TALKS

Joongseek Lee, Sangah Park, <u>Jisu Ryou</u>, Sumin Kwon, Jiseon Yu (2022). "사용 할수록 지식베이스가 성장하는 대화형 서비스 만들기", *HCI KOREA 2022 Tutorial*.

SKILLS

Programming: Python(high), JavaScript(high), C(intermediate), C++ (intermediate), Java(intermediate), C#(low)

Technical: HTML/CSS(high), SQL(intermediate), R(intermediate), Dialogflow, Google Cloud Platform

Design: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, XD, Figma

Language: Korean(native), English(fluent)